export const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: `
How many players are on a football team on the field?`,
    options: ['A) 11', 'B) 10', 'C) 12', 'D) 9'],
    answer: 'A) 11',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: `
    What is the name of the main football tournament?
`,
    options: [
      'A) Super Cup',
      'B) Europa League',
      'C) Nations Cup',
      'D) World Cup',
    ],
    answer: 'D) World Cup',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: `
   What sport uses a stick?`,
    options: ['A) Hockey', 'B) Football', 'C) Rugby', 'D) Volleyball'],
    answer: 'A) Hockey',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: `
    Which country won the 2022 FIFA World Cup?`,
    options: ['A) France', 'B) Argentina', 'C) Brazil', 'D) England'],
    answer: 'B) Argentina',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: `
    Which sport is an Olympic sport?`,
    options: ['A) Table tennis', 'B) Paintball', 'C) Chess', 'D) Baseball'],
    answer: 'A) Table tennis',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: `
     How many points does a three-point shot in basketball score?`,
    options: ['A) 1', 'B) 2', 'C) 3', 'D) 4'],
    answer: 'C) 3',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: `
    Which court is the smallest?`,
    options: ['A) Swimming', 'B) Cycling', 'C) Boxing', 'D) Athletics'],
    answer: 'D) Athletics',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `
    What is the name of a through ball kick in football?`,
    options: ['A) Panenka', 'B) Bicycle', 'C) Drive', 'D) Pass'],
    answer: 'B) Bicycle',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: `
    Who has the most Formula 1 titles?`,
    options: [
      'A) Lewis Hamilton',
      'B) Michael Schumacher',
      'C) Fernando Alonso',
      'D) Max Verstappen',
    ],
    answer: 'A) 11',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: `
    Which country won the 2022 FIFA World Cup?`,
    options: ['A) France', 'B) Argentina', 'C) Brazil', 'D) England'],
    answer: 'B) Argentina',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: `
   What are the "big four" in tennis?
`,
    options: ['A) Davis Cup', 'B) Masters', 'C) Grand Slam', 'D) ATP 500'],
    answer: 'C) Grand Slam',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: `
     Which country is the birthplace of sumo?`,
    options: ['A) China', 'B) Japan', 'C) South Korea', 'D) Thailand'],
    answer: 'B) Japan',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: `
    Which sport has a "strike"?
`,
    options: ['A) Bowling', 'B) Rugby', 'C) Golf', 'D) Baseball'],
    answer: 'D) Athletics',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: `
   What is a "time-out"?`,
    options: ['A) Overtime ', 'B) Foul', 'C) Double count', 'D) Halftime'],
    answer: 'D) Halftime',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: `
    What number did Michael Jordan wear?`,
    options: ['A) 7', 'B) 23', 'C) 10', 'D) 3'],
    answer: 'B) 23',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: `
    Which sport is played on ice?
`,
    options: ['A) Floorball', 'B) Badminton', 'C) Volleyball', 'D) Curling'],
    answer: 'D) Curling',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: `
     How long does a football match last?
`,
    options: [
      'A) 90 minutes',
      'B) 60 minutes',
      'C) 120 minutes',
      'D) 75 minutes',
    ],
    answer: 'A) 90 minutes',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: `
    Where are the Olympic Games held every 4 years?
`,
    options: [
      'A) In Greece',
      'B) Only in the USA',
      'C) In different countries',
      'D) In ​​London',
    ],
    answer: 'C) In different countries',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: `
    What color belt is the highest in karate?`,
    options: ['A) Blue', 'B) White', 'C) Green', 'D) Black'],
    answer: 'D) Black',
    category: 'Sport',
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: `
    What is the name of the game with a ball and hands through a net?`,
    options: ['A) Volleyball', 'B) Handball', 'C) Baseball', 'D) Racquetball'],
    answer: 'A) Volleyball',
    category: 'Sport',
  },

  {
    id: 21,
    question: `
Who wrote "Harry Potter"?`,
    options: [
      'A) J.K. Rowling',
      'B) Suzanne Collins',
      'C) Stephenie Meyer',
      'D) Veronica Roth',
    ],
    answer: 'A) J.K. Rowling',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: `
    The main character of the novel "1984"?
`,
    options: [
      'A) Jay Gatsby',
      'B) Jon Snow',
      'C) Winston Smith',
      'D) Paul Atreides',
    ],
    answer: 'C) Winston Smith',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: `
   The author of "The Master and Margarita"?`,
    options: [
      'A) Fyodor Dostoevsky',
      'B) Leo Tolstoy',
      'C) Anna Akhmatova',
      'D) Mikhail Bulgakov',
    ],
    answer: 'D) Mikhail Bulgakov',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: `
   What are the characters in "The Hobbit" looking for?`,
    options: [
      `A) The Dragon's Treasure`,
      'B) The Golden Fleece',
      'C) The Ring of Time',
      'D) The Magic Book',
    ],
    answer: `A) The Dragon's Treasure`,
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: `
    Who wrote "Anna Karenina"?`,
    options: ['A) Chekhov', 'B) Leo Tolstoy', 'C) Pushkin', 'D) Dostoevsky'],
    answer: 'B) Leo Tolstoy',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: `
     Which novel opens with the phrase "Call me Ishmael"?`,
    options: [
      'A) The Great Gatsby',
      'B) The Old Man and the Sea',
      'C) Moby Dick',
      'D) White Teeth',
    ],
    answer: 'C) Moby Dick',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: `
   How many parts are there in The Hunger Games?
`,
    options: ['A) 4', 'B) 2', 'C) 3', 'D) 5'],
    answer: 'C) 3',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: `
    Which book features the character Gandalf?`,
    options: [
      'A) The Lord of the Rings',
      'B) Harry Potter',
      'C) Narnia',
      'D) Game of Thrones',
    ],
    answer: 'A) The Lord of the Rings',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: `
    What genre is Sherlock Holmes?`,
    options: ['A) Drama', 'B) Romance', 'C) Fantasy', 'D) Detective'],
    answer: 'D) Detective',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: `
    Who is the main character in Pride and Prejudice?`,
    options: [
      'A) Elizabeth Bennet',
      'B) Jane Eyre',
      `C) Scarlett O'Hara
`,
      'D) Margaret Mitchell',
    ],
    answer: 'A) Elizabeth Bennet',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: `
  Who was Huckleberry Finn?
`,
    options: [
      `A) Tom Sawyer's friend`,
      'B) Detective',
      'C) Fictional pirate',
      'D) Apprentice',
    ],
    answer: `A) Tom Sawyer's friend`,
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: `
     Author of Crime and Punishment?`,
    options: ['A) Chekhov', 'B) Gogol', 'C) Dostoevsky', 'D) Turgenev'],
    answer: 'C) Dostoevsky',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: `
   Which book talks about the "Big Brotherhood"?
`,
    options: [
      'A) Brave New World ',
      'B) 1984',
      'C) World',
      'D) Fahrenheit 451',
    ],
    answer: 'B) 1984',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: `
   What is Tolkien's wizard's name?`,
    options: ['A) Sargassum', 'B) Grimdores', 'C) Baldur', 'D) Gandalf'],
    answer: 'D) Gandalf',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: `
    Who has a lightning bolt scar?`,
    options: [
      'A) Percy Jackson',
      'B) Harry Potter',
      'C) Jason Bourne',
      'D) Tom Sawyer',
    ],
    answer: 'B) Harry Potter',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: `
   What is Dr. Seuss' real name?
`,
    options: [
      'A) Lewis Carroll',
      'B) James Barrie',
      'C) J.K. Rowling',
      'D) Theodore Geisel',
    ],
    answer: 'D) Theodore Geisel',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: `
     What book is called a “dystopian”?
`,
    options: ['A) 1984', 'B) Harry Potter', 'C) Twilight', 'D) The Hobbit'],
    answer: 'A) 1984',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: `
    Who is the author of “The Wizard of Oz”?
`,
    options: [
      'A) John Tolkien',
      'B) Lewis Carroll',
      'C) Lyman Frank Baum',
      'D) Hans Christian Andersen',
    ],
    answer: 'C) Lyman Frank Baum',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: `
    What book has Thomas Cabin in it?`,
    options: [
      'A) The Little Prince',
      'B) Uncle Tom’s Cabin',
      'C) Billy Budd',
      'D) The Scarlet Pimpernel',
    ],
    answer: 'B) Uncle Tom’s Cabin',
    category: 'Books',
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: `
    What is read “aloud” in Bradbury’s book?`,
    options: [
      'A) Nothing — books are burned',
      'B) Classic literature',
      'C) Prayers',
      'D) Government orders',
    ],
    answer: 'A) Nothing — books are burned',
    category: 'Books',
  },
];
